<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Marko Kevac Home</title>
    <link>http://marko.kevac.org/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Marko Kevac Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 16:44:49 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://marko.kevac.org/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Encrypted DNS</title>
      <link>http://marko.kevac.org/posts/encrypted-dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 16:44:49 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marko.kevac.org/posts/encrypted-dns/</guid>
      <description>This is a bunch of notes taken from “DNS over HTTPS considerations” by Bert Hubert.
It’s an amazing talk and I recommend watching it. It covers the history of DNS security, privacy considerations, state-of-the-art and what awaits us in the future.
 DNS is one of the oldest text protocols that are still widely used. Almost everything else we encrypted already.
There have been four tries to encrypt DNS:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Blog (Hello World)</title>
      <link>http://marko.kevac.org/posts/new-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 00:31:40 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marko.kevac.org/posts/new-blog/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve decided to rekindle my blog as my New Year&#39;s resolution. I am going to leave Google&#39;s Blogger behind and switch to a static site generated by Hugo. You are reading a first post in a new blog. Welcome!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ssh_exchange_identification connection reset by peer problem</title>
      <link>http://marko.kevac.org/posts/ssh-exchange-identification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 14:08:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marko.kevac.org/posts/ssh-exchange-identification/</guid>
      <description>At Badoo we have a distributed system that uses ssh on start to connect to each node and exchange some data.
Sometimes I&#39;ve seen ssh fail with error
ssh_exchange_identification: read: Connection reset by peer error Usually, If you see this error, it means that server didn&#39;t like your certificate or you were banned from accessing this server.
The best way to debug this problem is to append -vvv while executing ssh client to increase verbosity and to do the same on server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memory Mappings Limit</title>
      <link>http://marko.kevac.org/posts/memory-mappings-limit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 18:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://marko.kevac.org/posts/memory-mappings-limit/</guid>
      <description>We have some very strange memory corruption problem in one of our daemons. As one of the many approaches to find the bug, we have built and pushed to production this daemon, but without jemalloc, memory allocator library that we use in all our projects.
Few hours after the release monitoring team reported an unusal amount of errors returned from the system. It happens that few percent of the requests returned &amp;ldquo;out of memory&amp;rdquo; error.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>